Speier, Hans; Papers ger084
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Correspondence files, 1911-1988; 3; 378 folders
  - Conquest, Robert, 1968 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 39)
  - Cooper, L. Charles, 1973 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 40)
  - Coser, Lewis A., 1977-1981 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 41)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, Inc. (John J. McCloy, Harold van B. Cleveland, David MacEachron, George S. Franklin, Jr., Rolland H. Bushner), 1954-1970 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 42)
  - Craig, Gordon A., 1979-1980 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 43)
  - Cropsey, Joseph, 1952 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 44)
  - D, E -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 45)
  - Dalma, Alfons, 1971 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 46)
  - Davis, Elmer, 1948 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 47)
  - Dethleffsen, Erich, 1956-1979 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 48)
  - Deutsch, Ernst and Joe Glenn, 1946 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 49)
  - Dickey, Thomas, 1973 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 50)
  - Dickler, Robert A., 1981-1982 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 51)
  - Dinerstein, Herbert S., 1982 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 52)
  - Dorn, Walter L., 1936 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 53)
  - Duggan, Stephan, 1947 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 54)
  - Earle, Edward Mead, 1944 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 55)
  - Eckardt, Wolfgang von, 1946 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 56)
  - Effertz, Margarete, 1938; 1945 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 57)
  - Eisenberg, Elliott, 1973-1980 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 58)
  - Eliasberg, George J., 1947 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 59)
  - Emmet, Christopher, 1971 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 60)
  - Epstein, David S., 1944 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 61)
  - Erdmann, Karl D., 1971 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 62)
  - Erler, Fritz, 1964 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 63)
  - F, G -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 64)
  - Factor, Regis A., 1980-1982 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 65)
  - Feit, Ewald, Undated (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 66)
  - Field, Henry, 1943 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 67)
  - Findley, Paul, 1969 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 68)
  - The Ford Foundation (H. Rowan Gaither, Jr), 1951 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 69)
  - Fox, William T. R. (Institute of War and Peace Studies, Columbia Univ), 1970 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 69)
  - Franz, Marie Anne von, 1983 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 70)
  - Friedrich, Carl J., 1943 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 71)
  - Gaither, H. Roman, Jr. (The Ford Foundation), 1951 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 72)
  - Geiger, Theodor, 1933 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 73)
  - George, Alexander (Alex) L. and Julie, 1946; 1956-1988; Undated (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 74)
  - Gerth, Hans H., 1938; 1973; Undated (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 75)
  - Gideonse, Harry D., 1974 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 76)
  - Gode von Aesch, Alexander, 1940; 1947 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 77)
  - Goldhamer, Herbert, 1955-1981 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 78)
  - Goldsen, Joseph M., 1956-1982 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 79)
  - Goldstein, Jacob R., 1945 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 80)
  - Goldstein, Thomas, 1981; 1984 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 81)
  - Gorer, Geoffrey, 1943 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 82)
  - Grathoff, Richard, 1974-1977 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 83)
  - Greenson, Ralph R., 1970; 1977-1978; reprints (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 84)
  - Greffrath, Mathias, 1976-1977 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 85)
  - Grewe, Ambassador Wilhelm G., 1969 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 86)
  - Grudin, Robert, 1970-1982 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 87)
  - Guerster, Eugen, 1947 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 88)
  - G -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 89)
  - Haag, John, 1973 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 90)
  - Haase, Arthur, 1946 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 91)
  - Habermas, Jurgen, 1970 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 92)
  - Hamilton, Charles, 1968 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 93)
    Re: 14 autograph letters from Speier's collection, auctioned by Hamilton. Includes copies of letters by: Siegfried Wagner; E. Maurice; August Wilhelm, Prince of Prussia (to Adolf Hitler); Geli (Raubal), Hitler's niece); Otto Wagener; Eva Braun; Fritz Sauckel.
  - Hamson, Knut, autograph only, Undated (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 94)
  - Hartshorne, E. Y. (Ted), 1946 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 95)
  - Heimann, Eduard, 1946-1947 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 96)
  - Herma, John L., 1945 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 97)
  - Hessler, William H. (Foreign Policy Association of Cincinnati), 1947 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 98)
  - Hinske, Norbert, 1975 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 99)
  - Holborn, Hajo, 1936 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 100)
  - Hollander, Paul and Gayle, 1972-1973 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 101)
  - Homann, Harold, 1983 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 102)
  - Hovde, Bryn J., 1946 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 103)
  - Howard, John, 1971 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 104)
  - Hula, Erich, 1946 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 105)
  - Hull, Cordell, 1939 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 106)
  - Hurwitz, Harold, 1969-1982 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 107)
  - I, J -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 108)
  - Ichheiser, S., 1940 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 109)
  - Iklé, Fred C., 1969-1985 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 110)
  - Inoki, Masanichi, 1963 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 111)
  - International Biographical Archives and Dictionary of Central European Emigrés, 1933-1945; 1979 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 112)
  - Isakson, Evelyn, 1975-1976 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 113)
  - Jakobson, Roman, 1947 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 114)
  - Johnson, Alvin, 1933; 1944-1946 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 115)
  - Jonas, Klaus W., 1969-1970 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 116)
  - K -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 117)
  - Kardos, Péter, 1984 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 118)
  - Katz, Barry M., 1980 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 119)
  - Kecskemeti, Paul, 1948-1949; 1970-1980 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 120)
  - Kellen, Konrad, 1969-1981; Undated (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 121)
  - Kellermann, Henry J., 1969-1986 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 122)
  - Klineberg, Otto, 1943 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 123)
  - Knappstein, Ambassador H., 1965 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 124)
  - Kocka, Jürgen, Undated; 1973-1975 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 125)
  - Kocka, Jürgen, 1976-1987 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 126)
  - König, René, 1979 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 127)
  - Koerner, Auguste, 1946 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 128)
  - Kolodziej, Edward A., 1969 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 129)
  - Kommers, Donald P., 1971 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 130)
  - Korte, Hermann, 1987-1989 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 131)
  - Kramish, Arnold, 1985 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 132)
  - Krautheimer, Richard, 1971; 1974 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 133)
  - Kris, Ernst, 1943-1947 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 134)
  - Krohn, Claus-Dieter, 1987-1988 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 135)
  - L -- miscellaneous corrrespondence, Undated (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 1)
  - Lasky, Melvin J., 1983 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 2)
  - Lederer, Emil, 1911-1925 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 3)
    (copies), 1938; untitled manuscript.
  - Lederer, Gertrud, 1971 (copy); 1982 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 4)
  - Leigh, Robert D., 1942-1943 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 5)
  - Leites, Nathan, 1943-1957 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 6)
  - Lepsius, M. Rainer, 1974-1986 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 7)
  - Lerner, Max, 1944 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 8)
  - Lewin, Kurt, 1945 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 9)
  - Lewis, Michael, 1973-1982 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 10)
  - Likert, Ron, 1945 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 11)
  - Livingston, Robert Gerald, 1969-1971 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 12)
  - Loose, Gerhard, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 13)
  - Lowe, Adolph, 1943-1945 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 14)
  - Lowenthal, Leo, 1947; 1968; 1980 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 15)
  - Lowenthal, Richard, 1968 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 16)
  - Luckmann, Benita, 1979-1986 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 17)
  - Ludwig, Ruth, 1959-1987 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 18)
  - Ludz, Ursula, 1981-1988 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 19)
  - Lübke, Heinrich (President, FDR), 1965 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 20)
  - Lüschen, Günther, 1978 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 21)
  - Lyman, Stanford M., 1977; 1981 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 22)
  - M -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 23)
  - Maier, Hans, 1970 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 24)
  - Maier, Joseph, 1978 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 25)
  - Mangold, Werner, 1979-1980; offprint (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 26)
  - Mann, Thomas, 1929 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 27)
  - Marschak, Jacob (Jascha), obituary, 1977 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 28)
  - Marschak, Marianne, 1977-1979 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 29)
  - Marshall, Charles Burton, 1969 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 30)
  - Martin, Daria, 1987-1988 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 31)
  - Martin, Richard (Dick) J., 1975 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 32)
    Dissertation proposal.
  - Matthiesen, Ulf, 1983; 1986 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 33)
  - Mecklenberg, Frank, 1985 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 34)
  - Meja, Volker, 1986-1987 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 35)
  - Mendershausen, Horst, 1965-1966 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 36)
    (includes interviews: Wolfgang Wagner, Helmut Schmidt, Alfons Dalma, Eberhard Schulz, Stefan Thomas, Egon Bahr, Klaus Ellrodt, Jim O'Donnell, K. Schütz, Jean-Paul Picaper, Pierre Hassner, Martin Rexin, Harold Hurwitz, Otto Frei, Willy Brandt, Kurt Leopold).
  - Menorah Lecture Bureau, 1933-1935 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 37)
  - Merton, Robert K., 1974; 1988 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 38)
  - Murphy, Robert H., 1974 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 39)
  - N-R -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 40)
  - Nerlich, Uwe, 1969; 1974 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 41)
  - Neumann, Sigmund, 1944-1946 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 42)
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1944 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 43)
  - North, Cecil C., 1936-1938 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 44)
  - Paasche, Maria and John, 1959-1983 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 45)
  - Page, Charles H., 1959-1983 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 46)
  - Parsons, Talcott, 1945 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 47)
  - Pool, Ithiel de Sola, 1982 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 48)
  - Priester, H. E., 1947 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 49)
  - Prinz, Michael, 1986; 1989 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 50)
  - Pütz, Karl Heinz, 1982 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 51)
  - Quint, Howard, 1981 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 52)
  - Radbruch, Professor, 1947 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 53)
  - Riesman, David, 1988 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 54)
  - Riess, Curt, 1947 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 55)
  - Riesterer, Beate S., 1974-1980 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 56)
  - Riezler, Kurt, 1943-1952 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 57)
  - Ritter, Klaus, 1969 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 58)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1944; 1975 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 59)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1955-1956 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 60)
  - Romoser, George K., 1970-1981 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 61)
  - Rosenberg, Jan, 1972-1974 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 62)
  - Rosinski, Herbert, 1944 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 63)
  - Rutkoff, Peter, 1984 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 64)
  - S -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 65)
  - Saame, Otto, 1976 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 66)
  - Salomon, Albert, 1944; Undated (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 67)
  - Schatz, Oskar (Oesterreichischer Rundfunk), 1969 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 68)
  - Schifrin, A., 1944 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 69)
  - Schluchter, Wolfgang, 1986 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 70)
  - Schroeter, Gerd, 1971-1981 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 71)
  - Schuman, Frederick L., 1943-1944 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 72)
  - Senger und Etterlin, Frido von, 1956; typescript (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 73)
  - Sereno, Renzo, 1954; typescripts (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 74)
  - Shils, Edward, 1943; 1970-1980; typescript (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 75)
  - Shubert, Gustave H. (Rand Corporation), 1985-1988 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 76)
  - Sibley, Elbridge, 1936; 1945 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 77)
  - Simons, Hans, 1947 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 78)
  - Smith, Bruce L., 1946-1947 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 79)
  - Sondin, Robert, 1979 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 80)
  - Spalek, John M., 1976-1978 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 81)
  - Sprondel, Walter M., 1980-1983 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 82)
  - Srubar, Ilja, 1983-1984 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 83)
  - Staudinger, Hans, 1943-1944; 1974-1978 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 84)
  - Stehr, Nico, 1984-1987 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 85)
  - Stern, Carola, 1969 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 86)
  - Sternberger, Dolf, 1983 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 87)
  - Strasser, Hermann, 1987 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 88)
  - Strauss, Harold (Alfred A. Knopf), 1946 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 89)
  - Strauss, Leo, 1946-1968 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 90)
  - Strauss, Max, 1954 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 91)
  - Strecker, Gabriele, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 92)
  - T, U, V -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 93)
  - Taft, Donald R., 1946-1947 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 94)
  - Tate, General Robert F., 1958 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 95)
  - Taurer, Bernhard, 1952 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 96)
  - Tenbruck, Friedrich H., 1976-1989 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 97)
  - Thompson, Wayne C., 1975-1980 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 98)
  - Tillich, Paul, 1947 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 99)
  - Toynbee, Arnold, 1968 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 100)
  - Trout, B. Thomas, 1970 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 101)
  - Ulmen, G. L., 1980-1984 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 102)
  - Unruh, Fritz & Friederike von, 1945-1947 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 103)
    Reviews.
  - Vagts, Alfred, 1971 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 104)
  - Vidich, Arthur, 1974-1986 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 105)
  - Voegeli, René and Erika, 1979-1982 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 106)
  - Völckers, Johannes, 1987 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 107)
  - von Kleist, Ewald, 1969-1973 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 108)
  - W-Z -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 109)
  - Wallenberg, Hans, 1946 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 110)
  - Walsh, John P., 1947 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 111)
  - Walther, Peter Th, 1980 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 112)
  - War College of the Air University, 1961 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 113)
  - Warnecke, Steven, 1969-1970 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 114)
  - Weber, Marianne, 1946; Undated (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 115)
  - Weizsäcker, C.F. Freiherr von, 1968 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 116)
  - Westcott, Marcia, 1976-1986 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 117)
    Curriculum vita.
  - Wettig, Gerhard, 1969 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 118)
  - Wheeler-Bennett, John W., 1943 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 119)
  - The White House, 1964 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 120)
  - White, Howard B., 1969 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 121)
  - Wilson, Robert N., 1971 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 122)
  - Windesheim, Hans, 1946 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 123)
  - Wittebur, Klemens, 1983 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 124)
  - Wolbers, H. L., 1972-1974 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 125)
  - Wood, Frank H., Jr., 1947 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 126)
  - Woodard, James W., 1936 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 127)
  - World Academy of Art and Science, 1969; 1975 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 128)
  - Wunderlich, Frieda, 1947 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 129)
  - Yerkes, Robert M., 1945 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 130)
  - Zeisel, Hans, 1977 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 131)
  - Zink, Bert, 1974-1983 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 132)
  - Miscellaneous book orders, 1969-1987 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 133)
  - Correspondence relating to financial matters, 1947-1983 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 134)
  - Correspondence relating to medical matters, 1971; 1976 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 135)
  - Travel arrangements, 1946-1986 (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 136)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified correspondence, Undated (Box 4 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 137)
  - Correspondence with publishers, editors, etc., 3.268
    - The American Journal of Sociology, 1947 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 1)
    - The American Political Science Review, 1957-1976 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 2)
    - The American Sociological Review, 1937 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 3)
    - Associated Faculty Press, Inc., 1984-1986 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 4)
    - Central European History, 1970-1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 5)
    - Contemporary History, 1986 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 6)
    - Current History, 1947 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 7)
    - Correspondence relating to the article "The Fool in Literature", 1967-1968 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 8)
    - Diogène, 1953 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 9)
    - Ferdinand Enke Verlagsbuchhandlung, 1932 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 10)
    - Frederick A. Praeger, Inc. re: Divided Berlin, 1961 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 11)
    - The Free Press, 1975 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 12)
    - The German Quarterly, 1981 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 13)
    - Harper & Row re:German Rearmament and Atomic War, 1966-1967 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 14)
    - JAI Press, Inc., 1982 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 15)
    - Journal of Political and Military Sociology, 1980 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 16)
    - Luchterhand Verlag, 1970-1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 17)
    - M.I.T. Press, 1967-1977 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 18)
    - New York Times, 1939 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 19)
    - Orbis, 1969 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 20)
    - Oxford University Press, 1943; 1988-1989 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 21)
    - Policy Sciences, 1971; 1983 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 22)
    - Polity (Peter J. Fliess), 1971-1981 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 23)
    - Princeton University Press, 1970; 1981 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 24)
    - Public Opinion Quarterly, 1972 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 25)
    - Random House, Inc., 1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 26)
    - Rombach & Co. GmbH, 1972 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 27)
    - Social Research (Arien Mack), 1971-1979 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 28)
    - Studies in Comparative Communism, 1969 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 29)
    - Südwestfunk, 1970 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 30)
    - University of Chicago Press, 1946 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 31)
    - University of Massachusetts Press, primarily re:From the Ashes of Disgrace (Richard Martin), 1978-1987 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 32)
    - University of Pennsylvania Press, 1970-1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 33)
    - Vandenhoeck & Ruprecht (Winfried Hellmann), 1974-1986 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 34)
    - Verlag A. Fromm, 1974-1984 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 35)
    - Verlag W. Kohlhammer, 1972 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 36)
    - Worldview, 1972 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 37)
    - Yale University Press, 1985-1987 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 38)
    - Zeitschrift für Sozialforschung, 1931 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 39)
  - Correspondence with co-editors (Harold Lasswell and Daniel Lerner) and contributors to Propaganda and Communication in World History, 1968-1983; 3.269
    - Barbu, Zev, 1968; 1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 40)
    - Barton, Robert, 1972 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 41)
    - Bouwsma, William F., 1970 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 42)
    - Brentano, Robert, 1969-1970 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 43)
    - Céspedes, Guillermo, 1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 44)
    - Darnton, Robert, 1972 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 45)
    - Davison, W. Phillips (Phill), 1971-1983 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 46)
    - Deutsch, Karl, 1971-1973 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 47)
    - Douglas, Richard N., 1970 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 48)
    - Eisenstadt, S. N., 1970-1972 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 49)
    - Eisenstein, Elizabeth L. (Betty), 1970; 1981 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 50)
    - Erikson, Erik, 1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 51)
    - Finkelstein, Jacob J., 1971-1972 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 52)
    - Finley, M. I., 1972 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 53)
    - Forman, Charles W., 1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 54)
    - Gay, Peter, 1972-1973 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 55)
    - Goffmann, Erving, 1971 (Box 5 (3-Correspondence files), Folder 56)